Felipe Ignacio Diaz Alburquenque

Software Developer Engineer



linkedin.com/in/fdiazalburquenque/



felipediazalburquenque@gmail.com



www.serranderx.com



Santiago (Chile)

EXPERIENCE

2019 - Present Full Stack Senior Developer

Xintec LTDA

Development, maintenance and implementation of software, using agile methodologies in technologies with monolithic architecture and microservices.

2019 - 2014

h

Support and computer consulting.

ChileRad LTDA

Level three computer support and system operations maintenance in tele-radiology

TOP PROJECTS

2023 - Present **Automation and digital transformation**

Cencosud - Full Stack Developer Senior

Development of an automation system for logistics needs, brings analyze, data management and centralization, among others business solutions.

NestJS • ReactJS • Azure • AWS • PostgresDB • ArgosCD • Gitlab

CI/CD • Azure AD • Redis • Spring boot

2023 - 2023 Planilla Pagos - Others

Sodimac SA - Full Stack Developer

Development, maintenance and implementation of logistic solutions and payment to suppliers through microservices.

NodeJS • ExpressJS • AngularJS • Oracle DB • ArgosCD • MongoDB

• SonarQube • GitLab • Azure AD • Redis • Spring boot

2022 - 2023 **Sisalud**

Clinica Alemana SA - Full Stack Developer

Development, maintenance and implementation of software aimed to satisfy the needs of the clinic health-informatics systems at a national scale.

JAVA 8 • Spring framework • Spring boot • Oracle DB • Weblogic

Server • JUnit

2019 - 2022 Servicio de apoyo a nuevos procesos (SANP)

Fiscalia nacional - Full Stack Developer

Development, maintenance and implementation of software for a centralized system of administration and follow-up of judicial cases at a national scale.

JAVA 8 • Spring framework • Spring boot • Oracle DB • JBOSS

Server • SonarQube • JUnit • AngularJS - Angular 8

EDUCATION

2017- 2021 Informatics and computer Engineer

Universidad Tecnológica de Inacap. Santiago de Chile

2017 - 2019 Tecnical developer analyst

Universidad Tecnológica de Inacap. Santiago de Chile

STATEMENT

With more than four years of experience as a software developer in various technologies performing work in a Full Stack Senior position, also having knowledge in IT as a general, offering consulting services in monolithic and cloud integration.

Currently studying the framework of DevOps and Cloud Delivery Services.

SKILLS

Software Development

- Advanced Knowledge in Java | Spring Boot | ReactJS | NextJS | NodeJS | NestJS | Angular | AngularJS | Python
- Mobile applications Android | Ionic
- Relational and not relational Databases PostgreSQL, MySQL, OracleSQL, MongoDB
- Version Control Softwares like TortoiseSVN
 | GIT | GITHUB | GITLAB
- Advanced knowledge on transpilers and code compilers like Webpack | Babel
- Advanced knowledge of continuos integration and condinuos deployment like Docker | Kubernetes | Jenkins | GITLAB CI | ArgosCD | AWS

Personal

- Capable use of English on a Written and Conversational level A2 – B1
- Knowledge of UI/UX
- Capable use of Agile Methodologies

Certifications & Badges



Curso de Next.js: Autenticación

Platzi

Expedición: oct. 2022 · Sin fecha de vencimiento



Curso de Next.js: Optimización y Manejo de Grandes Datasets

Platzi

Expedición: oct. 2022 · Sin fecha de vencimiento



Curso Profesional de Docker

Platzi

Expedición: abr. 2023 · Sin fecha de vencimiento



Curso de Next.js: Internacionalización de aplicaciones Web con i18n

Platzi

Expedición: sep. 2022 · Sin fecha de vencimiento



Curso Profesional de Git y Github

Platzi

Expedición: sep. 2022 · Sin fecha de vencimiento



Curso de Next.js: Optimización y Deploy en Producción

Platzi

Expedición: ago. 2022 · Sin fecha de



Curso de React.js: Patrones de Render y Composición

Platzi

Expedición: dic. 2021 · Sin fecha de vencimiento



Curso de introducción a React.js

Platzi

Expedición: sep. $2021 \cdot Sin$ fecha de vencimiento



Curso de Gestión de Dependencias y paquetes con NPM

Platzi

Expedición: jul. 2021 · Sin fecha de vencimiento



Curso de Fundamentos de TypesScript 2020

Platzi

Expedición: ago. 2021 · Sin fecha de vencimiento



Curso de Next.js: Seguridad Web con OWASP

Platzi

Expedición: nov. 2022 · Sin fecha de vencimiento



Curso de Frameworks y Librerias de Javascript

Platzi

Expedición: ago. $2021 \cdot Sin$ fecha de vencimiento



Curso de ECMAScript 6+

Platzi

Expedición: jun. 2021 · Sin fecha de vencimiento



Curso de Clousures y Scope Javacript

Platzi

Expedición: jun. 2021 · Sin fecha de vencimiento



Curso de Asincronismo con Javascript

Platzi

Expedición: jul. 2021 · Sin fecha de vencimiento



Curso Profesional de JavaScript

Platzi

Expedición: ago. 2021 · Sin fecha de vencimiento



Curso de Webpack

Platzi

Expedición: ene. 2022 · Sin fecha de vencimiento



Curso de React.js: Manejo Profesional del Estado

Platz

Expedición: ene. 2022 · Sin fecha de vencimiento



Curso de NestJS: Programación Modular, Documentación con Swagger y Deploy

Platzi

Expedición: feb. 2021 · Sin fecha de vencimiento



Curso de Backend con NestJS

Dlatai

Expedición: abr. 2021 · Sin fecha de vencimiento

Certifications & Badges



Curso de Frontend Developer

Platz

Expedición: ene. 2021 · Sin fecha de vencimiento



Curso Práctico de React.js

Platzi

Expedición: ene. 2022 · Sin fecha de vencimiento



Curso Profesional de React.js y Redux

Platzi

Expedición: abr. 2022 · Sin fecha de vencimiento



Curso Profesional de React Hooks

Platzi

Expedición: abr. 2022 · Sin fecha de vencimiento



Curso de Unit Testing con Jest en React

Platzi

Expedición: may. 2022 · Sin fecha de vencimiento



Curso de React Avanzado

Platzi

Expedición: may. 2022 · Sin fecha de vencimiento



Curso Práctico de Javascript

Platzi

Expedición: may. 2022 · Sin fecha de vencimiento



Curso Práctico de Frontend Developer

Platzi

Expedición: may. 2022 · Sin fecha de vencimiento



Curso Práctico de Next.js

Platzi

Expedición: ago. 2022 · Sin fecha de vencimiento



Curso de Next.js: Sitios Estáticos y Jamstack

Platzi

Expedición: ago. 2022 · Sin fecha de vencimiento



Curso de Fundamentos de Angular

Platz

Expedición: jul. 2022 · Sin fecha de vencimiento



Curso de Manipulación del DOM

Platzi

Expedición: jun. 2022 · Sin fecha de vencimiento



Curso de Next.js

Platzi

Expedición: jun. 2022 · Sin fecha de vencimiento



Curso de Progressive Web Apps con React.js

Platzi

Expedición: jun. 2022 · Sin fecha de vencimiento



Lifelong Learning

CertiProf

Expedición: ago. 2021 · Sin fecha de vencimiento



Scrum Foundation Professional Certificate (SFPC)

Platz

Expedición: mar. 2022 · Vencimiento: mar. 2024



Curso Profesional de React.js y Redux

Platzi

Expedición: feb. 2024 · Sin fecha de vencimiento



Curso de Java: Backend con Spring Boot

Platz

Expedición: jun. 2023 · Sin fecha de vencimiento



Curso de Fundamentos de Python

Platzi

Expedición: mar. 2024 · Sin fecha de vencimiento



Curso de Python: Comprehensions, Funciones y Manejo de Errores

Platzi

Expedición: mar. 2024 · Sin fecha de vencimiento